# LUKEMITCHELL

# CURRICULUM VITAE

Updated July 30th 2020

#### ABOUT ME

A software developer, UI designer, technology consultant and a blue-sky thinker. I've worked as a cryptocurrency developer for a number of small FinTech startups, as a website freelancer for multiple small businesses and as a lead developer for larger companies on multiple client-facing projects. I'm a creative thinker, self motivated and an experienced team leader. I've developed a hobby operating system, several cryptocurrencies and a magnetic stylus for guiding the user as they point. I speak basic German.

I enjoy travelling, climbing, taking photographs, living sustainably and practicing yoga. I've cycled 2400 kilometers across the Alps and I've hitchhiked across Europe. During 2018 I lived nomadically in India, Sri Lanka, Nepal, Japan and Malaysia.

# **EMPLOYMENT**

# Ebase / Verj.io

September 2019 to date

I am currently working as a product consultant for a low-code platform. I am presently the lead developer on a client project.

Skills: JavaScript, UI, web, back-end, front-end

#### Enki

July 2016 to July 2017 (1 year)

I worked as a full-stack developer with Enki, developers of a microlearning app for teaching developer skills. I began by using JavaScript, CSS and React to create a hybrid iOS/Android application within a small team. We then rewrote the application using React Native. The role also included website and database admin, toolchain development and feature design.

Skills: Node.js, React, React Native, web, back-end, front-end, gamification

# **University of Bristol: Research Contractor**

May 2016 to July 2016 (6 weeks)

I was enlisted by my dissertation supervisors to assist a research project after the completion of my degree. The project, named *IODiCUS*, involved creating a generic gateway to be used for the intelligent analysis of power usage and generation across the university estates, with the aim being a reduction in consumption and cost. During this time I created test frameworks, performed refactoring and aided in design decision-making.

Skills: Software design, Linux, Python, Node.js, Docker

# **Technology Consultant**

February 2014 to May 2018 (4 years)

I worked as a freelance consultant, specialising in developing cryptocurrency applications for FinTech startups. I have worked with other developers and, latterly, as a technical adviser to launch products including a gold-backed blockchain, an encrypted messenger with an integrated wallet and an array of supporting software. Former clients included Mothership.cx, The Real Asset Co. and StartCOIN Holdings Ltd.

Skills: Software design, UI, JavaScript, C++, web, mobile, cryptocurrency

# Cambridge Consultants: Technology Scholar

September 2010 to September 2012 (1 year, 3 months)

I spent a year working as an intern with Cambridge Consultants before starting my degree. During this time I was a member of several internal development teams including an intern-led project developing a 'whitespace' WiFi network. I worked on client projects including a testing framework for the Highways Agency, a UI mockup for Novartis and a survey framework.

Skills: Software development, project organisation, C#, PHP, Linux, wireless

#### **VOLUNTEERING**

### Feed Bristol

June 2017 to December 2017 (6 months)

I am currently volunteering at the Feed Bristol project, an organisation promoting sustainable agriculture, wildlife conservation and education about the ecosystem. The project runs as a smallholding and the daily tasks include digging and plot management, harvesting, seed saving, seed sowing and conversation.

# **Hungry Caterpillar Food Co-op**

September 2012 to June 2016 (3 years 9 months)

I was the president of a student not-for-profit co-operative. The organisation helps students make ethical food choices by providing a weekly pop-up shop selling organic and fairtrade produce, sourced from local suppliers. The co-operative has dozens of members and the organisation requires social media management, stock-taking and charisma. We were awarded the Volunteers for Food award at the Bristol Green Volunteering Awards in March 2016.

# **Callington Road Psychiatric Hospital**

December 2012 to April 2013 (4 months)

I have volunteered for an organisation that visits a psychiatric hospital to talk to patients, play games with them and generally alleviate the monotony of hospital life. I found this to be a challenging and moving experience that I enjoyed immensely.

#### Other

I have also volunteered at projects including Food Cycle, the Bristol University Sustainability Team and the COP21 march.

# **PUBLICATIONS**

Force Attraction Pen: A Haptic Pen with Variable Attraction Force, Burnside, Elgar, Healer, Hill, Ioannidis, Mitchell, Worgan and Roudaut. In Proceedings of CHI EA'16. Late Breaking Work. 2016.

#### **EDUCATION**

**MEng Computer Science** (Second Class Honours: First Division)

University of Bristol July 2016

Final project: "A Digital Platform for Conducting Research into Social Pledges"

A level Computer Science, Maths, Philosophy (Grades A, A, B)

AS level Electronics (Grade A)

Hills Road Sixth Form, Cambridge June 2010

# REFEREES

**Dr. Chris Preist**Reader in Sustainability
University of Bristol
chris.preist@bristol.ac.uk

Dr. Julian Gough
Professor of Bioinformatics
University of Bristol
julian.gough@bristol.ac.uk

Jon Edgcombe
Group Leader
Cambridge Consultants Ltd.